FESTUS EFOSA ERIAMIATOE

919 Ridge DR, Apt 2-12

DeKalb, IL 60115

eriamiatoefestus@gmail.com, 773-704-8936.

linkedin.com/in/efosa-eriamiatoe-53903968

CAREER OBJECTIVE

Proactive and well-trained Quantitative Economist and Data Analyst, with over 5 years' experience in data gathering, cleaning, analyzing and interpretation using major econometrics/statistical software such r, python, Microsoft power BI, SPSS, E-View and Microsoft Excel. I am confident that my skills and Knowledge will help achieve your organization set goals.

EDUCATION

•	Master of Science in Statistics	Expected May (2022)
	Northern Illinois University, USA	
•	Master of Art in Economics	2021
	Northern Illinois University, USA.	
•	Master of Science in Economics	2016
	University of Benin.	
•	Bachelor of Science in Adult Education/Economics and Statisti	cs 2011
	University of Benin.	

ACADEMIC RESEARCH PAPERS

- Logistics and Trade Flows in Selected ECOWAS countries: An empirical investigation. http://www.ijsrp.org/research-paper-1121.php?rp=P11911799
- The Effects of Health Expenditures on Life Expectancy in Selected SSA Countries; An empirical verification. (In progress).
- The interactive effect of the evil triplet: Climate change, armed conflict and forced displacement. Does macroeconomic performance matter (In progress).

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Northern Illinois University, Illinois

2019-Date

Position: Graduate Assistant

Roles and responsibilities:

- Collect, analyze, and interpret data result using statistical/econometrics techniques and presenting results using R, python, SAS, Latex and power point.
- Follow establish course outline to prepare lessons and convey information and enhance understanding of materials.

- Adhere to University requirements for students' assignments, testing and grading of work.
- Utilize email, phone and in-person meetings to answer questions and mentor struggling students.

Notre Dame industrial company Nigeria Limited.

2018-2019

Position: Procurement/General duty Officer

Roles and responsibilities:

- Devise and use fruitful sourcing strategies,
- Discuss profitable suppliers and initiate business and organization partnership,
- Discuss with external vendors to secure advantageous terms,
- Approve the ordering of necessary goods and services,
- Finalize details orders and deliveries,
- Control risk management for supply contracts and agreements.

Flourish Group of school, Benin City

2016-2018

Position: Head of Social Sciences

Roles and responsibilities:

- Prepare and deliver lectures on Economics for senior secondary school classes.
- Prepare course materials such as syllabi and homework.
- Evaluate and grade student's classwork and assignments.
- Compile, administer and grade student's examination.
- Maintain student's attendance records.
- Initiate, facilitate, and moderate classroom discussion.
- Maintain regularly scheduled office hours to advise and assist students.

God's City Global Ventures

2013-2016

Position: Financial Controller

Roles and responsibilities:

- Managing all finance and accounting operations
- Coordinating and directing the preparation of the budget and financial forecast and report
- Preparing and publishing timely monthly financial statements using excel sheet.
- Carry out internal Audit.

Simplex Academy 2012-2013

Position: Administrative Officer

Roles and responsibilities:

- Ensure proper keeping of Staffs and student records.
- Served in academic and administrative committee that deals with institutional policies, departmental matters, and academic issues.
- Participate in the recruitment of students and Staffs.

SKILLS

- Data Analyses
- R programming
- Python,
- Stata,
- Microsoft SQL
- E-view,
- SPSS
- SAS
- Microsoft office
- Presentation
- Strong communication skill

TRAINING CERTIFICATES

- Introduction to Cloud computing (Udemy)
- Introduction to Linux (Udemy)
- Using SQL for data science (Udemy)
- Microsoft power Bi (Udemy)
- Python for data science (Udemy)
- R programming for data science (Udemy)
- AZ 303 Microsoft Azure Architect Technology (Udemy)
- AZ 304 Microsoft Azure Architect Design (Udemy)